<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PCA - R version</title>
      <link>/post/pca-r-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/pca-r-version/</guid>
      <description>library(tidyverse) library(knitr) opts_chunk$set(engine.path = &#39;/anaconda3/bin/python&#39;)  Load proteomics data The sample dataset is dim(scan) matrix.
scan = read.csv(&#39;/Users/DL/Documents/Jupyter project/Somascan Protein Creatinine/somascan.csv&#39;) X = (scan[,c(4:35)]) # Scale and center - z score -- column wise xscale = (apply(X, 2, scale)) plot(attr(scale(X), &amp;quot;scaled:center&amp;quot;)) x &amp;lt;- xscale[, 4] y &amp;lt;- xscale[, 5] z &amp;lt;- xscale[, 30]  Distance dist() computes and returns distance matrix for pairwise samples stored in the rows of data matrix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git basics</title>
      <link>/post/git-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/git-basics/</guid>
      <description>Online tutorial for Git 
Some basic commands Add-commit-push  git add -u :/ # adds all modified file changes to the stage; analgus to get files monitored by git. git add * :/ # adds modified and any new files (that&amp;rsquo;s not gitignore&amp;rsquo;ed) to the stage git commit -m &amp;lsquo;your commit comment&amp;rsquo; # equivalent to save the file git commit -am &amp;lsquo;your commit comment&amp;rsquo; # perform add and commit git push origin master # or just git push origin master  Check history  git status # consistency status with branch master, changes not staged for commit, untracked file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principle component analysis vs support vector machine</title>
      <link>/post/priciple-component-analysis-vs-support-vector-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/priciple-component-analysis-vs-support-vector-machine/</guid>
      <description>Background This spreadsheet contains urine proteomic data normalized to creatinine (relative fluorescent units of protein per mg of creatinine) with 4 groups: 1) Febrile UTI), 2) nonfebrile UTI, 3) culture negative pyuria (white blood cells in the urine) and 4) culture negative normal UA
We are looking for a panel of protein/creatinine levels that predicts UTI (group 1 and 2 combined) when compared to both culture negative pyuria (group 3) and culture negative, normal UA (group 4) individually and in combination</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief introduciton on intialization of a website using the R blogdown package</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>An useful short video introdution/guide is provided here.The website will be hosted by github webiste and administered using Netfily.com server. Some basic background knowledges may involve:
 Markdown syntax Github account Git1 Git2 Blogdown  Set up a new repository on github The Github.com is where you will upload and store all the static documents for your website. Suppose you have already set up a github account. The creation of a new repository is straightforward, nothing other than inputting some basic repository info.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>